I bought a week's worth of vegetables at the market~.
This week we will show you how to prep your vegetables to make them last longer.
By the way, how many times a week do you go shopping?
I like to go shopping frequently, but it's hard work.
Buying and prepping in bulk makes cooking easier and saves money by reducing unnecessary shopping.
Oh, I bought carrots and then I bought them again at a different store because they were cheaper. LOL!
And onions--the ones at the market are big and fresh!
And yet, I just ended up buying this one too!
These 3 bags were 50 yuan 😂I love the market, it's like treasure hunting.
Mushrooms are always at the whole lian. It is cheaper and fresher that way.
I bought some delicious looking Korai greens! I want to have a hot pot of hot pot this weekend.
Broccoli is good for weight loss, one is going to eat it today.
Always check the roots! I pick the ones that are packed, nicely colored and heavy.
Komatsuna is another favorite vegetable, I bought 2 bunches because it was 10 yuan per bunch.
Bok choy was also 10 yuan. I plan to put it in soup.
Now, we have one hour left to trudge.
If you do this, it will be easy to cook a week's worth of meals.
First, cheap and nutritious bean sprouts.
Transfer to a bowl and wash under running water thoroughly.
Bean sprouts are one of the most common vegetables that get hurt very quickly. In our house, if you wash them thoroughly like this...
Drain in a colander
Stasher glue sealed bag 站站 series large size
Put bean sprouts in it.
Please see the U R L of the Dan purchase in the summary section for the stasher.
Please check out our past videos for more details on how to use this product.
Then you fill it up with plenty of water from the water purifier.
If you change the water every two days, it will last from 3 to 7 days, depending on freshness.
If the sprouts are fresh today, they will last 7 days.
Stasher has a great mouth seal.
Put into refrigerator in this condition. You can eat crispy bean sprouts anytime.
Komatsuna is nutritious and low in carbohydrates. It is a food my family eats often.
First, shake off the soil at the base of the roots a little stronger under running water
Turn over and wash the leaf tips well.
It is easier and quicker to use vegetables if they are all washed first.
Then place them in a colander to drain.
Chives are also washed from the root.
And the leaf tips. It's like shaking to remove dirt.
The aromatic greens are floated in running water while the damaged leaves are plucked off.
Wash them under running water and rinse them off.
The base of the bok choy is cut off, so just jab here.
Four cucumbers, rinsed thoroughly.
One cucumber is put in salted rice-bran paste, and three are kept refrigerated.
beans
green onion
Okra soaked in water
Scallop shell powder
Sprinkled with
I'm a little concerned about pesticides, so I leave it on.
Broccoli is also left in shell powder.
I also put it in water and shake it off because there might be bugs.
The washed ones are taken to a colander as they are washed.
Tomatoes and carrots are also washed.
Corn is bought with skin as much as possible.
The taste of the corn deteriorates with each passing hour after harvest, so it is recommended to prep the corn as soon as you buy it.
After washing off more and more, put them in a colander.
After washing, the water is so dirty.
Mako has woken up~
Meow
I had been suffering from constipation recently, but after changing food, my energy was restored.
Now I am having a good bowel movement every day again.
Oh, he's gone 😂.
Sushi chef's dish towel
After wetting with water
Lay in enamel container
Put aromatic herbs as they are
Wipe chives well with a dish towel
Roots are hard and muddy, so cut off and cut into usable pieces.
Chives are a leafy vegetable that easily lose their freshness. It is recommended to consume it as soon as possible. If you don't use it right away, put it in a storage bag and freeze it. The texture will not change much.
Use up in 3 or 4 days in an enameled container lined with a wet dish towel.
Green onions, too, are thoroughly wiped dry.
After cutting off the root, cut into white part and blue part.
After removing the dirty part at the root
To the same enameled container
Put the wet vicinity on one side also on top, put the lid on, and then put it in the fridge
The dishcloth keeps just the right amount of moisture to keep leafy greens fresh. You can wet them a little when you open and close them.
The blue parts are often scattered or floated in soups.
It is chopped up.
It is easier to cut them together if you wrap the leaves in a cloth to keep them from falling apart.
It's a pain to chop them every time you use them, so I always do it this way, and they usually last 4 or 5 days in the fridge.
If you want to keep them longer than that, put them in a storage bag and freeze them. The texture will change a little, but the taste will not.
It is convenient because you can put it in stir-fry, omelet, or anything else right away.
Enameled containers are lined with wet kitchen paper.
Put chopped green onions in it.
Top with more wet kitchen paper to hold it down.
Put the lid here and put it in the refrigerator.
Wipe off the water on the broccoli buds and put them in the refrigerator.
This product sold at DAISO etc. (toothpicks can be substituted)
If you stick it in the root part of broccoli, it stops it from growing and delays the pain.
Wrap it in a dry cloth.
I N to medium size of stasher logistics series!
It will last about a week in refrigerated storage, depending on freshness.
If you want to keep it longer, you can cut it and freeze it, but it will lose its texture, so it is good if you use it for soup.
Next time, you also put a wet dish towel on an enameled container.
After draining well, cut the root of komatsuna, and put it in a bowl.
Cut into stems and leaves
Into enameled containers
If you keep them in the fridge in the bag as you bought them, they'll only last about two days, but they'll last
In this condition, it will last 4 or 5 days in refrigerated storage.
The trick is to cover the top with a dish towel as well. The condensation on the lid will damage the vegetables faster.
After cutting off the root of another bunch of komatsuna, chop them finely.
I N to medium size of stasher 站站 series!
If you don't plan to use them right away, or if you bought a lot at a discount, freezing them is recommended. they will last 2-3 weeks. they can be stored in the freezer for up to 3 weeks. they can also be stored in the refrigerator for up to 3 weeks.
I always use them frozen when I make soup. It is super convenient because I don't have to wash and cut them.
Next, I put a wet cloth on an enameled container.
The root of bok choy is cut off because of its muddy smell, and cut into easy-to-eat size
If it is cut and put in enamel, it is convenient to use in various ways such as stir-frying, soup, and small bowl dishes with a little lenching.
When I was unable to touch water due to an autoimmune disease, this batch prep method took the stress out of cooking.
If you are concerned about the nutrients flowing through the vegetables, freeze them; they will last 2-3 weeks, but the texture will change.
Cover with a wet cloth to prevent soreness, cover with a lid, and refrigerate.
Next, 2 big carrots
Cut off the head and buttocks and they stop growing
Wrap them in a dry cloth because they are sensitive to water. This way, they are not exposed to condensation water and keep the right amount of humidity.
Stasher vertical type
Then stand it up in the stasher vertical form and seal it
Stand it up and store it in the refrigerator, it will last more than a week.
Silicone bags are firm and easy to store standing up.
Three cucumbers are thoroughly wiped dry
Wrapped in dry kitchen paper
Put in a stasher large oblong shape with the buds facing up
Sealed
Stands upright and stored in refrigerator
Wipe okra well and cut off the stem.
If it's too much trouble, you can cut off okra at right angle.
Put water in a pot and put it on fire.
Okra is not suitable for refrigeration, so I boil half of it and eat it right away.
The other half is cut into thin round slices.
If you don't eat immediately, freezing is recommended.
Cut into pieces the size to eat like this and freeze fresh in a stasher.
Then when you eat it, you can defrost it and eat it uncooked.
It takes about a month to freeze, depending on the freshness of the fish.
Now let's see, stasher squares.
Put the sliced raw okra so that it lies flat
If vegetables are well drained, freeze in a stasher so they don't stick together.
After freezing, it looks like this
Green beans are also cut off at the head and buttocks.
Green beans are indispensable for salad, salad, stir-fry, and colorful in simmered dishes.
However, it is a summer vegetable that is susceptible to dryness and cold, so the standard preparation is to boil it hard as soon as you buy it.
Take off the heta
Tomatoes are bought in bulk when they are cheap. Sometimes I marinate them, sometimes I dry them.
Make a criss-cross cut on the skin
I like to peel tomatoes in hot water because the skin of Taiwanese tomatoes is very hard compared to Japanese ones and it leaves a residue in the mouth.
Corn is split with a light slit in the middle
Make a large bowl of ice water.
Put tomatoes in boiling water
After 30 seconds to 1 minute, when the skins start to roll up, put them in ice water to cool
This prevents the inside from being overcooked by residual heat.
Next, salt is added to the pot
Boil green beans
Boil hard, so pull them up quickly after 20 seconds or so
Put in ice water to cool
Okra also same 20 seconds or so
To ice water
Finally, corn
Enameled containers are lined with dry kitchen paper
You can season them, but if you don't know how you are going to eat them, just boil them in salt.
Put a piece of kitchen paper underneath to absorb excess water.
Depending on the freshness, I keep them in the refrigerator and only eat them up in a couple of days.
Tomatoes are peeled and
(This time, I keep them as they are in the refrigerator, but they are also delicious in soup stock or marinated.
It is good for 3 or 4 days in the refrigerator, depending on its freshness.
Corn is now ready to be boiled.
Pulled out of hot water
Biodegradation wrap
Wrap while hot
Corn can be fresh or boiled, frozen or refrigerated.
You can do it any way you like, but I freeze it in a stasher after it has recovered from the residual heat.
Shiitake mushrooms are carefully cleaned with a wet cloth.
Wash shiitake mushrooms with water to remove the flavor.
Half is sliced into thin strips and frozen
Freezing further breaks down the cell membranes and increases the amount of nutrients that are released.
If you have time, you can dry mushrooms in the sun for an hour or so to increase the vitamin D content.
Half of the mushrooms are divided into four equal parts
This one is cooked and prepared for immediate consumption.
Add maitake mushrooms to this one - maitake mushrooms are easily hurt, so if you don't use them right after you buy them, you should freeze them or heat them up.
And shimeji shimeji
Cut off the shaft part
Put them in a stasher with shiitake mushrooms and freeze them
Snow salt
Maitake mushrooms and shiitake mushrooms with plenty of furikake
Kyoto Chidori Vinegar
a little
Cold-pressed extra virgin olive oil*See Summary section
cod
Mix well
Put on silicon wrap.
Microwave 600w , 2 minutes
After mixing
The simple marinated mushrooms are ready.
You can eat them as they are, or use them in stir-fries, soups, anything.
Store in the refrigerator and eat up in 4 or 5 days
Next is enoki mushrooms.
Cutting off the shaft in the bag
Wash in running water with bag still in place
Squeeze well
Drain and put into a heat-resistant silicon bowl
Enoki mushrooms are also vulnerable to moisture and low temperatures, and are easily damaged. And it doesn't taste good when frozen.
So I cook them as soon as I buy them.
Microwave 600w for 2 minutes passed~.
Mix well because the heat is still uneven
salt from algae
Sesame oil
Mix well
If it is cooked and lightly seasoned like this, it can be used in many dishes.
It is very convenient to eat it as it is, or take it out and use it immediately as a dressing, or as an ingredient in miso soup, etc.
The quantity decreases when cooked, so even two packs are quickly eaten up.
Big, fresh onions wrapped in a dry cloth for a stasher.
Potatoes not used immediately are removed from the bag
Wrapped in dry kitchen paper with mud and put in a stasher with onions
Onions and potatoes don't like moisture and cold, so I guess it's like giving them clothes.
If you put them in the refrigerator in this condition, they will last lightly for 3-4 weeks depending on their freshness.
4 small onions that were cheap
Heads and butts cut off and peeled
Like this
You can cut them into small pieces, but I haven't decided what I'm going to use them for yet, so I'm going to freeze them whole.
It can be frozen for more than a month, so I recommend freezing them when they are cheap.
If you put them in a stasher and freeze them, you don't have to wrap them one by one and they don't stick together, so you can use them one by one.
Next is pumpkin.
Lightly wash the skin part
Wrap in a wet cloth and put into a heatproof bowl
Cover with heatproof silicone wrap and microwave at 600w
4 minutes to make it a little harder.
Hard outer skin is now softened
Hot and juicy
Seeds are removed with a spoon (be careful, they are hot!)
The buttocks and head can be easily cut off
Now you can cut it into pieces that are easy to use.
You can make a stew in five minutes, cut it into small pieces and put it in a soup, or cut it into small pieces and put it in a salad, and you can take it out right away and use it easily.
Pumpkin doesn't taste good when frozen, so we don't do it in our house.
We put them in storage containers like this and eat them up in 3 or 4 days.
Now, the cabbage is removed only from the outer leaves that are sore, and lightly washed.
I'm going to let it sleep until the weekend.
Use a small knife to hollow out the core. Because the core absorbs nutrients from the leaves and shrivels up.
in the hollowed out part.
Press a wet dish towel into the hollowed-out area
I wrap it in newspaper to prevent condensation, and then I put it in a bag, but I don't have any newspaper.
I store them in a double layer of washed and dried bags.
Two small carrots bought cheap, cut into small pieces.
Put them in a stasher
If you freeze it as it is, it makes soup life easier every day.
Oh, and watch the previous video about soup life.
One cucumber is made into a pickle.
This is our small bed of rice bran
Cucumbers pickled the day before are taken out and the bran is washed off
Stir well
New cucumbers I N!
I recommend my nakudoko because fermented foods are good for you, easy to make, and delicious!
Check out my previous videos if you like!
See also the extra video on how to preserve ginger...
You can keep it for a couple of weeks if you put it in a stasher and soak it in water.
This is how garlic is stored
Buy in bulk and put straight into the stasher without peeling
By the way, these are for immediate use in the refrigerator. They will last 3-4 weeks depending on freshness.
These are frozen. If fresh, it will last more than 6 months.
By the way, if you are a stasher, you don't have to wrap each one individually.
And it doesn't freeze inside. You can cut the buttocks with a little bit of light force.
And then soak it in water for about 5 minutes to thaw it out.
And the skin comes off easily like this.
If you freeze them chopped or grated, they don't taste good because they get freezer burn.
This is the recommended way to store them for a long time and use them deliciously
Preparation of bought vegetables - it's done!
An hour's hard work of buying the food will make a week's cooking easier
I freeze what I don't use right away.
If you store them upright in the vegetable compartment, they will last up to a week.
Prepared for immediate use, it keeps the refrigerator clean and easy to remove.
Red, green, yellow, and various colored foods can be easily incorporated in a well-balanced way.
Corn is also ready to eat after thawing at room temperature. It can be used for cooking or as a snack if you are hungry.
Just shove whatever vegetables you have left over into the rice bran - lol!
I cut leafy greens into small, easy-to-use pieces so I can take them out and use them right away.
Cover them with a wet cloth so that condensation water doesn't fall on the leaves.
You should know what's in it, so you don't forget to use it.
Put cabbage in the vegetable room with the roots facing down.
Cucumbers and carrots are stored upright
Remember, leafy greens are in enameled containers
No leakage of water if you put bean sprouts in a stasher
You can put leafy greens, broccoli, etc. in the top shelf, too.
Garlic, ginger~
So how was it? I would be happy if I could give you some hints to make your daily cooking a little easier.